There are many ways that machine learning algorithms can
在纯粹的数据驱动法做预测过程中
be used in purely data driven approaches for prediction.
有多种方式使用机器学习算法
Since you already went through a machine learning class,
因为大家已经上过机器学习课
we won't go into these techniques in too much detail.
所以这里我不再详细讲述
But in this video,
但是 在本视频中
I would like to show you one example that is representative
我将向大家展示一个例子 这个例子表现出
of what these algorithms are good at...
这些算法擅长的方面 - 轨迹聚合
As is the case with all data driven prediction techniques,
通常 使用纯数据驱动法的过程
there will be two phases.
会划分为两个阶段
An offline training phase where the algorithm learns a model from data
第一个阶段是离线训练阶段 在此阶段中 算法从数据中学习模式
and online prediction phase where it uses that model to generate predictions.
第二个阶段是在线预测阶段 在此阶段中 算法使用模型来生成预测
Let's discuss the offline phase first.
我们首先来讨论离线阶段
The first step is to get a lot of data which you
第一步是获取大量数据
might do by placing a static camera at an intersection.
这可以通过在交叉路口放置一个固定摄像头来实现
Then, we have to clean the data since some of the cars we
然后 我们还得清理数据 因为有些车辆也许会被遮挡住
observe may be occluded or something else went wrong in the processing step.
还有些车辆在处理过程中也有错误数据产生
So we need to discard the bad data.
所以我们需要丢弃无效数据
Once the data is gathered and cleaned up,
当数据被收集并且清理干净后
we would be left with a bunch of trajectories that look something like this.
我们就会得到很多轨迹 看起来是这样的
Next, we need to define some mathematical measure of
接下来 我们需要定义一些数学上的轨迹相似性测量
trajectory similarity and there are many ways to do this but intuitively we want
有很多种方式来定义
something that says a trajectory like this one in red is more
但是我们想要一种更加直观的方式
similar to this one in pink than it is to this one in blue,
来告诉我们 红色轨迹和粉色的更相似 和蓝色不太相似
even though they're red and blue trajectories overlap
尽管在一段时间里 红色和蓝色靠得很近且有重叠
more closely for a while than the red and pink ever do.
但是 红色和粉色仍然具有更大相似性
If you're interested in learning more,
如果你想要学习更多相关知识
I will include a link to a paper that discuss measures of similarity in detail,
我会给大家一篇论文的链接 该论文详细论述了相似性测量
but once we have a measure of similarity we can use a machine learning algorithm
但是 一旦我们有了相似度测量 我们就能够使用一个机器学习算法
like agglomerative clustering or a spectral clustering to clustered these trajectories.
例如 凝聚聚类或者谱聚类 来聚合这些轨迹
In the case of a four-way stop intersection,
在一个四方向交叉路口
we would expect to see 12 clusters since at each of
我们将期望看到12个聚合 因为在4个停车指示中的每一处
the four stop signs cars can do one of three things: turn right,
车辆可以做3种动作之一
go straight or turn left.
右转、直行、左转
So if we were looking at just one of those four stop signs,
所以 如果我们观察4个停车指示之一
we would expect to see a cluster of trajectories for left turns,
我们期望看到一个轨迹聚合
going straight, and turning right.
包含左转、直行、右转的轨迹
Note that in some situations you may obtain even more clusters than that.
注意 在一些情况下 你也许会得到更多的聚合
For example, if this lane is controlled by a traffic light instead of stop,
例如 如果这条车道由交通信号灯控制 而不是停车标志来控制
your clustering algorithm will probably create twice as many clusters.
聚合算法可能会创建之前两倍的轨迹聚合数
Three of them go through the intersection without
其中三条不停车通过路口
stopping and three of them stop at the traffic light first.
另外三条会先在信号灯前方停车 然后再通过
Once the trajectories have been grouped in too clusters,
一旦轨迹被分组到聚合中
it is useful to define what prototype trajectories look like for each cluster.
对每一个聚合定义那些原型轨迹将很有用
For the left turn cluster,
对于左转的聚合
maybe these three trajectories are a good model.
也许这三条轨迹将是一个不错的模型
They provide a compact representation of what
它们提供了在此路口
left turns typically look like at this intersection.
左转车辆的典型运动路径
At this point, we have a trained model of typical car behavior at this intersection.
目前 我们已经有了一个此路口车辆典型行为的训练模型
The next step is to use this model on the road to actually generate predictions.
接下来的步骤 就是在道路上使用此模型 并生成实际预测